You may be thinking, lifecycles are really important.
However this section, is on persisting and recovering data. Trust me,
I just want to get us coding again. However, these things are closely linked and
they're easy to get wrong if you don't understand both. As Reito mentioned,
Android saves the state of the application in bundles. You might have had
the idea that you would just save all sorts of information in these bundles and
not have to worry about any other form of persistence. But, the thing is,
these bundles go away as soon as the user hits the Back key in
your main activity. It's really important that they do this.
When the user chooses to close your activity with the Back key, the expectation
is that next time your activity is displayed, it will be in the default state.
If the user backgrounds your app using the Home key or the App Switcher,
the next time your activity is created, it should resume from the current state.